sunilkumarsheoran@gmail.com +1-6043674432

linkedin.com/in/sunilkumarsheoran

ECS 412, University of Victoria, Victoria, BC, Canada. V8P 5C2

I am a first-year post-graduate student at the University of Victoria with 3 years of full stack software development work experience with software product companies. I am seeking co-op opportunities where I can fully use my skills for the success of an organization and learn new skills on cutting edge technologies in the industry.

#### **Education**

M.Sc. in Computer Science Jan 2019 - Expected Dec 2020 University of Victoria, BC, Canada. - 7.33 / 9.0 GPA

**Projects**: DQN agent for Coinrun (git.io/JvB5r), Matchmaking for online multiplayer games (git.io/JenE4) and DOTA2 win prediction (git.io/JvB5P).

B.Tech. in Information Technology Aug 2010-May 2014

NIT Durgapur, West Bengal, India. - 8.10 / 10.0 CGPA Projects: Collage Study Point Website (git.io/JenEB), Digital Clock on Multisim and Exploration bot.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Languages: Java, JavaScript, Python, Golang, SQL, C/C++, CSS, HTML5.
- Tools & Frameworks: Docker, Kubernetes, PyTorch, gRPC, Git, REST, JSON, Google Web Toolkit (GWT), JDBC, Hibernate, Electron, AngularJS, Eclipse Modeling Framework (EMF), JasperReports, Excel, AWS.
- Concepts: OOPs, Data Structures, Machine Learning, Agile practices, Deep Learning.
- Operating Systems: Linux, Windows.

# **Experience**

#### Technical Associate / Zillious Solutions, New Delhi, India.

July 2018 - Dec 2018

- Developed a solution for a long-standing issue with java enum reaching its size limit, with minimum changes in the application.
- Added support for customizable vouchers and integrated multiple payment gateways including Razorpay, Paytm, etc.
- Integrated a pre-developed machine learning model into the application for finding duplicate hotels. Decreased the time for marking duplicate hotels by 90% in live search results for hotels.

### Software Developer / Drishti-Soft Solutions, Gurugram, India.

June 2014 - Sep 2016

- Awarded with Excellence Award 2016 and won /tmp 2014 a 10 days 24x7 coding event.
- Majorly worked on Ameyo Report, a GWT based front-end, and Jasper based backend; This includes a UI renew, backend
  enhancements and automating the generation of *Transformers*, a data de-normalization component, by using EMF modeling.
- Created a report scheduler based on the Quartz library with support for centralized reporting and graphical reports.
- Increased performance for a large customer's reporting database by 90% using table partition and multicolumn indexes.
- Increased performance of a statics managing component by 60% using soft references based cache for reflective calls.
- Developed a context-aware report designer with the Front-end based on GWT with data populating based on EMF model instances and outputs a proprietary file format (.drxml) which converted by the backend into a JasperReports based object. It was used to give demos to international customers as a future project.
- Created Magic Numbers: Predicts hardware requirements (CPU, RAM, and HDD) based on customer functional requirements.
- Delivered components for the automation of the collection process for an Indian Bank. Implemented a fresh UI, Integrating Hitachi Content Platform (HCP) for report storage, created a custom SSO authentication server & various domain-specific features like *Centralized Exclusion*.
- Interviewed candidates, prepared questions and did the training for new employees for the 2016 and 2017 hiring seasons.

## Software Developer Intern / Morphing Machines, Bangalore, India.

June 2013 - Aug 2013

• Designed and developed the front-end interface for a research project called 'Development of A Flexible Framework for A Network On Chip'. We wrote a research paper about it (git.io/Jen9I).

# **Personal Interests**

- Video Games: Won 2<sup>nd</sup> place in COBX and Aorus Land 2017 National DOTA 2 tournaments, 1<sup>st</sup> place in Playtonia Delhi and Indian LAN Gaming Cup Delhi DOTA 2 tournaments.
- Karate: Green belt in Shito Ryu Shūkōkai Karate.
- Solving Programming Problems: Won 1<sup>st</sup> place in *Behind the Scene* 2013, 1<sup>st</sup> place in *InCanity* 2013 and 2<sup>nd</sup> place in Simplex 2012.
- Playing Chess: 3<sup>rd</sup>, 1<sup>st</sup> and 2<sup>nd</sup> place in *Regional Sports Meet* in 2007, 2006 and 2005. Won a place in K.V. National Sports Meets.

## References

- Sahil Gandhi (sahilgandhi2011@gmail.com) Product Evangelist, Ameyo (previously known as Drishti-Soft Solutions).
- **Dr. Hausi Müller** (<u>hausi@uvic.ca</u>) Professor, University of Victoria.